You're an idiot.
It's bad enough you believed her, but then you gave up?
Please, forgive me Colonel.
You've gotta stay strong.
And don't you ever give up on living.
I need to know you can keep
your cool no matter what happens.
Sir.
I'm gonna continue to
rely on you to watch my back.
Don't let me down.
You oughta think about taking
your own advice, Colonel.
Since you were the one
who abandoned his post.
Hey! Shut up, Havoc—ow!
[GROANS]
And what the hell?
Why are we even in the same room?
At my rank I should have my own room.
With hot nurse...
Try to understand, sir.
It's easier to guard the
two of you in the same place.
Which reminds me...
Why haven't they tried to kill us yet?
What's wrong with you?!
How could you let that bastard go
after what he did?
You should've yanked his spine
out of his mouth!
Lust... He killed Lust...
It's not too late to kill him,
so get to it!
We can use Mustang.
He's worthless if we kill him, however.
Use him?
Hold on...
You mean the portal?
[CHUCKLES]
You don't need to worry about it
And forget Mustang.
Father wants me to handle him.
Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
nezumiiro no sora no shita
Higawari no chizu
ikutsumo no yume ga nijinde ita
Itsuka wa sa chippoke na
boku no kono hohaba demo
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
Tsuyogatte kizutsuita kokoro sukashita you ni
Furidashita amatsubutachi ga
ranhansha kurikaesu
Massugu na hikari ga kousa shite
Yukusaki mo tsugenu mama
dokomademo tsukinukeru
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakistukete
Kono sora no shita donna toko ni ite mo
Todoku hazu nanda mada minu sekai e
What if I've started to rot?
BOTH: Huh?
I doubt that my body's getting any nutrients...
or any sleep, either!
So even if we get it
back from over there...
[DISTORTED] Brother... Winry...
[SHRIEKS]
Is he right, Ed?
[SIGH]
Now this is just a hypothesis...
But I was thinking about the transmutation
and trying to retrace our process.
You remember how we mixed our blood
to create a blueprint for mom's soul?
Yeah.
Well, right after that
we passed through the portal,
where we were both deconstructed.
It's a slim chance...
But I think it's possible our spirits
might've gotten tangled up in the process.
What are you saying?
I'm trying to explain that our
bodies might be connected somehow,
even though I'm
here and your body's over there.
See...
That might actually explain why I'm so sh...
Sh...
Short.
- He admitted it.
- He's starting to face reality!
So...
You think you've been supplying
all the nutrients for Al's body, too?
That seems a little far-fetched.
Well what's your explanation?
You don't grow because
you refuse to drink your milk.
- Don't start with that again!
- Well, it's true!
It seems like brother is always sleeping...
I wonder if his body could
be resting for mine as well?
...you start drinking it, you have to!
- It's not gonna happen!
- Drink it!
No!
- Fine, stay a runt!
- [AL LAUGHING]
I'm not a runt!
I hope so, at least.
- ...Never!
- I'll make you!
- Just try!
Are you here to visit the Colonel?
Mr. Havoc is recovering too.
We figured we should pay our respects.
I definitely owe it to the Colonel.
He saved me right the last second.
Are you also dropping by for a visit?
And bringing a little present.
I counted the number of steps it took to get
to the basement under the Third Laboratory.
And I was able to calculate
the approximate location of that doorway.
It's not exact, since the hallway curved
But I was able to deduce a radius
with the lab at the center.
That's Central Command?!
But this is even more alarming...
It's the Presidential Estate.
Right above where we found
the homunculi.
Which means there's a very real possibility
the Fuhrer is connected to them.
But that doesn't make sense.
Why did he kill Greed and his group
if he's connected to them?
Strange he killed them anyway...
Why would he slaughter them
before interrogating them?
Strange, all right.
Damn inscrutable.
One thing's for sure, the enemy's infiltrated
high up the command.
So extreme caution is
necessary at all times
And Fullmetal?
- Watch yourself.
- [GASP]
The Fuhrer...working with the Homunculi...
This could be bigger
than I ever dreamed.
I'm starting to worry that it's too big.
All the more reason to pursue it.
So.
I hope you're ready
to work yourselves ragged.
Oh, yeah. About that, Colonel?
I think you're gonna have to count me out.
Your work requires legs
- And I can't feel mine.
- [GASPS]
I hate to say it,
but I'm retired.
Hello.
Hey.
What brings you down here?
Back problems.
My spine can't stand all the standing
that comes with being coroner.
I got a sinking feeling when I heard
you were the person that scorched that Thing.
Are you plotting something?
You suspect a plot, but you still ID'd the "thing" as Maria Ross.
Three cheers for old war buddies, huh?
Old war buddies, my butt.
More like accomplices.
You'd incinerate 'em
and I'd dissect what's left.
We treated them like rats
and Ishval was the lab.
I know you like to play with fire,
but someone'll get burnt
if you push this too far.
You should have warned me earlier.
Huh?
Did somebody get injured?
One of my men.
He was paralyzed.
From the waist down.
Damn.
They only let me smoke one of these a day,
and I go and waste it.
Jeez.
You know I thought I'd retire because
of a woman, but not like this.
So what happens next?
My family owns a grocery store.
And I can at least take calls.
Isn't automail an option?
The nerves in my lower spine
are completely severed,
and they can't make those out of steel.
Tch.
The retired life
doesn't suit you.
Colonel.
Hmm?
There's still hope for Havoc.
Fullmetal passed this onto me.
Dr. Marcoh, huh?
Medical alchemist in possession of a...
Philosopher's stone?!
Well, sir, should I find him?
Permission granted.
Get going.
Oh, Major!
Hmm?
I didn't expect
you back so soon.
How did you enjoy
your vacation to the east?
[GRUNTING]
Shh!
Loose lips sink ships, Major.
The scenery was luminous
and the women desirable.
Ha...
Uh, oh! Uh, before I forget,
this just arrived from the Provost Marshal's office.
It's an urgent bulletin
for all State Alchemists.
Good heavens!
How'd it go?
Easy.
I told them I was a State Alchemist and they
let me right in with no questions asked.
Did you find the basement?
There wasn't one.
[GASP]
But it did find a trace
of some hasty alchemy.
It was stupid of us to think that
they wouldn't seal up the entrance.
I guess so.
Where else are we gonna to find a
homunculus if we can get down there?
I'm not sure.
Remember how they told me I was their sacrifice,
and they needed me alive?
They told me the same thing.
Lust told me that when
she found out I opened the portal.
Well there's one piece of the puzzle.
They're looking for alchemists...
that managed to open the portal
and make it back out alive.
But the real question is
why they wanna sacrifice us.
So, we'll have to beat an answer out of them.
- Edward, wait!
- What the...
Is that Sergeant Brosh?
I'm glad I found you.
Yeah, why don't you tell me what's wrong?
You should go back to your hotel right now.
I can escort you if you want me to.
Attention all military personnel,
It has been verified that
Scar has returned to central.
Three casualties have been reported.
All confirmed as State Alchemists.
According to eyewitness reports,
he is described as an Ishvalan,
with an X-shaped scar on his forehead.
Other identifiable markings include
a tattoo on his right arm.
A tattoo.
It was him.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Fullmetal Alchemist.
So you're saying that
Scar killed Winry's parents?
I don't know for certain,
but that's the way it looks.
Poor Winry...
Brother,
you weren't planning on
telling her, were you?
Of course not, Al.
I couldn't stand to be the one
to make her cry again.
Neither could i.
It's the last thing I wanna do,
but we have to confront Scar
To find out if he did it?
Well, that's one reason.
But there is another.
We're gonna lure out the Homunculi.
[GASP]
They need us alive
for their sacrifice, don't they?
So I doubt they'll be willing to just
stand by while Scar kills us.
You think so?
Sounds like a pretty
big gamble to me.
Well it's much better
than doin' nothing.
Oh, really?
Because Scar literally torn us apart
the last time.
Well, we've...gotten stronger...
in these past few months...
What happens if the Homunculi do show up?
How are you gonna catch one?!
They're super strong,
and they pretty much can't die!
Can't die? Was that hyperbole?
Or are they actually immortal?
Why don't we lock the windows?
Count us in,
we'd love to help you guys.
Why's that?
I can't say I care about the military stuff,
but it sounds like these Homunculi are
just what we've been looking for.
What's wrong?
You look kindaskeptical.
Don't get me wrong, I am grateful for
the help you've already given...
- But this...
- You've got better odds with more help.
I'm serious about this.
This could be what
rescues my clan.
Alright then.
Just remember, we're in this together.
I promise not to
run off with them.
I owe you that much.
What for?
[CASH REGISTER DING]
- Is...this...for room service?!
Uhh... [NERVOUS LAUGH]
You're damn right you owe me!
[WINDOW SMASHES]
BOTH: Woo!
Will you guys shut up?!
Do you know how early
I have to wake up tomorrow?!
Oh right, I forgot!
You're catching an early train to Rush Va—
[GASP]
[METAL SMASHING]
Y'know what? You should cancel that.
Why don't you stick around and relax?
Huh?
I mean it's just that...y'know, well...
There's...
Always a chance my arm could get broken.
Or even...
destroyed...
[CRASH]
Are you planning on destroying it?!
ED: [WHIMPERING]
AL: I've got your soul, brother!
I can't believe you.
Just promise you won't
do anything too dangerous.
BOTH: Uh...
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[KNOCKING]
Hey, Doc.
Are you home?
I could use your help with something.
Huh?
Damn.
Is that so?
Report back to base.
Yet another dead end.
[DOOR OPENS]
Well, if you'll excuse me.
Who was that?
My mother, and an officer
from the veterans council.
I've decided to go
ahead with my retirement.
I don't know for certain if
your wounds are inoperable.
I'm not dumb enough
to think i have a chance.
I'm useless.
You're wrong.
Look, don't try and tell me
you need upon that can't move.
And don't you
look at me like that.
Forget about me.
Move on already.
You don't have time
to worry about me!
You need to think about the promise
you made General Hughes,
- instead of pitying me!
- Lieutenant Havoc!
Just let me get on with my life.
I beg you.
- All right.
- [GASP]
You're cut loose.
I'll leave you behind
so you can catch up.
I've got to keep moving,
but I'll see you at the top.
[DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
He doesn't give up.
He didn't even think about
turning his back on me.
And I had given up on living.
It's not in him to
abandon others.
He refuses to.
He's a fool.
He's not gonna make it to the top.
This country will chew him up
if he keeps on acting this soft.
Well I don't know about that.
This country needs
a fool like that man.
I need you to bring me my uniform.
But you're not ready to leave the hospital yet, Colonel.
Just go get it.
Right away, sir.
Oh that's my livelihood, you idiot!
U-Uh, I'm really sorry sir.
Ah, well sorry's not gonna fix my stand.
Looks like you could use some help!
BOTH: Huh?
It's a good thing I happened by!
Edward Elric: State Alchemist at large!
Wow, that's amazing!
Thank you very much, sir!
Please, you have to let me pay you for this.
Pay me?
Thats not necessary,
but thank you!
Could you please help me
with my broken vase?
It's a priceless family heirloom.
Why no problem at all! [CLAP]
[CROWD OOH'S]
[CROWD AHH'S]
That's right, I'm here to help!
I'm your friendly neighborhood State Alchemist.
Don't forget: I'm Edward Elric!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[SNEEZE]
[CHUCKLING] I'm pretty sure everyone in
Central knows my name by now.
Well you were a little over the top.
When did you become so theatrical, Fullmetal?
Colonel?
Shouldn't you still
be in the hospital?
Probably.
I heard about Lieutenant Havoc.
- I'm sure Doctor Marcoh—
- Hold on.
People are watching us.
Get in.
On second thought let's get out.
Dr. Marcoh's gone missing?
Looks like it.
They probably took him captive.
There's something else
we need to talk about.
I'm sure you've heard that Scar's back.
So what's with the showboating,
do you want him to find you?
Yeah that's exactly what I want.
I need to fight him,
and you can't talk me out of it.
Have you lost your mind?!
Did you forget the way he
tore you apart in East City?
Oooh, sounds like the Colonel's scared of big, bad Scar.
I'm not surprised considering how useless
you were against him! [LAUGHING]
That wasn't my fault,
it was raining that day!
Was it raining when you got
beat up and sent to the hospital?
You're still useless!
Shut you mouth, Fullmetal!
Guess he got your invite.
You okay?
He'd think it was raining
the way your forehead's dripping.
Hold it!
Don't shoot, Lieutenant.
What? You can't be serious?!
I'm trying out
the Colonel's sport.
Think I might be able to catch a few fish.
We're using brother as bait
to lure out the Homunculi
He's too important to them.
They can't afford to just let him die.
That's crazy!
We're not gonna let
anyone else get hurt.
Using ourselves as bait
was our only option.
What are you going to do
if Scar happens to get shot?
The MPs might get here before the Homunculi.
But you can stop that from happening.
Can't you, Colonel?
So now I take orders
from you, is that it?
You've got a lot of nerve.
You had better plan on
sharing what you catch.
Of course!
Hey, get out of the way!
We need a clear shot.
Don't shoot! You'll hit my brother!
Dammit!
Everything's lost if
those guys shoot Scar.
How long can I keep this up?
Way too close!
Hurry up, you stupid Homunculi!
Which channel's
the Provost Marshal's?
Got it.
You haven't let me down, Fuery..
Attention, this is Sector 3 patrol.
We're under attack from Scar,
request immediate backup—
What? No! No—[SCREAMS]
All right, onto Sector 17.
[GIGGLING]
This is pretty fun!
[LOW VOICE] Come in!
[DIFFERENT VOICE] Come in!
But that can't be right...
He's in Sector 17?
What about Sector 3?!
Colonel Douglas!
He's in Sector 8, now!
What's that?!
MP HQ calling Sector 8.
Scar is currently
fighting a young man.
The young man is
a State Alchemist.
Do not fire!
Multiple reports in all sectors!
We have reports of a fourth Scar!
This is Sector 3,
all streets are clear.
Sector 8 requesting backup!
Currently engaged with Scar!
Come now, Gluttony.
I smell the Ishvalan.
He's here,
I get to eat him, right?!
That's a strange presence.
You could feel it too, right?
Yes.
Then it's time to move.
Which will it be?
Is he gonna destroy
my body or my automail?
Brother!
Lucky!
He cancelled out Scar's alchemy!
How reckless can you get?!
He's got tattoo!
Bastard!
You were the one!
I smell him!
Time to eat!
Hi! How's it going?
That is one pretty unusual
body you've got there.
Just how many people
are inside you?
Oh, you!
Don't bother running.
I sense your presence.
And I can follow it.
Follow? Me?
Me?
Then I'll just eat you now!
There it is!
He's a Homunculus!
So,
you're able to detect
his presence, are you?
Well that's quite the nuisance.
Let's take care of it.
Lan Fan! Run!
No! Lan Fan!
Let it all out, let it all out
Tsuyogaranakute ii n da ne
Dareka ga kaite'tta
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
Jibunrashisa nante, dare mo wakaranai yo
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu
de nakushitari, hirottari,
Kyuu ni samishiku natte,
naichau hi mo aru kedo
Namida mo itami mo, hoshi ni kaeyou
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
Chiisana te kazashite
futari de tsukurou hoshikuzu wo
Tsuyoku hikaru ein wo
Sayonara itsuka wa kuru ka mo shirenu
Kisetsu wa sore demo meguri megutte'ku
Chiisaku mayotte mo aruite'ku
Kimi to aruite'ku
Sore daku wa kawaranaide iyou ne
The scream of the fallen girl pierces
every darkened corner of Central.
As the anguished debts of a violent history
are repaid with bloodshed,
the past and present reveal themselves
to be murderous reflections of one another.
Next time on Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood
Episode 22: Backs in the Distance
The young man realized... He'd do anything to protect her.